Vengeance Returns
Underworld: Awakening is a fantasy, action,
horror film directed by Måns Mårlind.
Having escaped years of imprisonment, vampire warrioress Selene finds herself in a changed world where humans have discovered the
existence of both Vampire and Lycan clans and are conducting an all-out war to eradicate both immortal species.
Now Selene must battle the humans and a frightening new breed of
super Lycans to ensure the death dealers' survival.
Selene, played by Kate Beckinsale.
Dr. Jacob Lane, played by Stephen Rea.
Detective Sebastian, played by Michael Ealy.
David, played by Theo James.
Eve, played by India Eisley.
Thomas, played by Charles Dance.
Underworld: Awakening is a 2012 American action horror film directed by Måns Mårlind
and Björn Stein from a screenplay by Len Wiseman, John Hlavin, J.
Michael Straczynski, and Allison Burnett, based
on a story by Wiseman and Hlavin.
It is the direct sequel to Underworld: Evolution (2006) and the
fourth installment in the Underworld film series.
The film stars Kate Beckinsale, Stephen Rea, Michael Ealy,
Theo James, India Eisley, and Charles Dance.
Principal photography began in March 2011 in
Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada.
Underworld: Awakening premiered at the Grauman's Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles, California on January
18, 2012, and was released in the United States on January 20, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics but was the highest grossing film in the Underworld
film series, grossed over $160 million worldwide against a production budget of $70 million.
The film was followed by Underworld: Blood Wars in 2016.
The film explores themes of daughter, experiment,
vampire, hybrid, child vampire.
The tone is dark.